Finding Aid for Hospitals (University of Michigan) records, 1875-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Nursing
  - Educational Services for Nursing
    - Phoenix Program 1983 (Box 155)
    - Policies
      - Educational Services 1982 (Box 155)
      - Procedures (Box 155)
      - Unit Policy 1973 (Box 155)
    - Problem Oriented System (Box 155)
    - Professional Achievement for Nursing Programs 1982-1989 (Box 155)
    - Project Reports (Box 156)
    - Resource for Nurses 1989-1993 (Box 156)
    - Resources Manual for Unit Shared Governance 1990, 1 binder (Box 157)
    - Retreat 1995, 1 binder (Box 157)
    - Role Transformation Workbook 1975 (Box 156)
    - Staff Development Review 1976-1979 (Box 156)
    - Teaching Strategies for Nurses (Box 156)
    - Woman's Facilities Planning 1984-1986 (Box 156)
  - Nursing Administration
    - Clinical Ladder (Box 133)
    - Continuing Care Committee, 2 folders (Box 133)
    - Continuing Care Committee, 1 binder (Box 136)
    - Goals and Objectives (Box 133)
    - Licensed Practicing Nurse (Box 133)
    - Mutual Gains Approach Proposal (Box 133)
    - Nursing Executive Council January 1989-March 1990, 10 folders (Box 133)
    - Nursing Executive Council April 1990-September 1992, 17 folders (Box 134)
    - Nursing Executive Council October 1992-1993, 3 folders (Box 135)
    - Nursing Orientation Program (Box 135)
    - Nursing Task Force (Box 135)
    - Organizational Charts (Box 135)
    - Orientation Manual (Box 135)
    - Photographs, 3 folders (Box 135)
    - Policy and Procedure Manual, 1 binder (Box 135)
    - Publications (Box 135)
    - Work Redesign Committee, 2 folders (Box 135)
    - Committee Records October 1988-December 1989, 2 binders (Box 136)
    - Committee Records January 1990-December 1991, 3 binders (Box 137)
  - Nursing Services
    - Director of Nursing Services, Search Committee 1970 (Box 38)
    - General Information Bulletin/Nursing Newsletter 1972-1979 (Box 38)
    - Manuals
      - Diagnostic Procedures Manual 1975-1980, 2 folders (Box 38)
      - Hospital Utilization Review 1968 (Box 38)
      - Patient Equipment Manual 1973 (Box 38)
      - Therapeutics Manual 1975-1980 (Box 38)
    - Minutes/Memoranda 1970-1981 (Box 38)
    - Nursing Needs 1965-1966 (Box 38)
    - Nursing Project
      - 1967 (Box 38)
      - 1970 (Box 38)
    - Organizational Structure, Joint Review Committee Report 1980-1981 (Box 38)
    - Orientation for Staff Nurses 1968-1969 (Box 38)
    - Patient Unit Management, Conference on Current Concepts 1969, 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Program for Change 1970-1971 (Box 38)
    - Staffing Reports 1972 and 1977 (Box 38)
    - Strike 1981 (Box 38)
    - 1985 accession: Linda Strodtman, collector (Box 38)
    - 1986 accession: Linda Strodtman, collector (Box 38)
    - Photographs (Box 38)
- Committees/Councils
  The Committees/Councils series (37 linear feet) contains materials on a number of committees of on the different functions within the many hospitals. The series is split into 10 subseries, each one offering documentation on the decisions and actions of specific committees. Each of the subseries solely contains minutes of the committee meetings, except in the case of the Medical Staff subseries which also consists of data and statistics compiled by this group. Records relating to the committees of the executive directors and executive board can be found in the Hospital Administration series.
  - Clinical Affairs and Financial Committee
    - Minutes March 1986-September 1988 (Box 83)
  - Clinical Chairman's Council
    - Minutes (Box 65)
      - December 1979-March 1981, 2 volumes (Box 65)
      - April 1981-July 1982, 4 volumes (Box 66)
      - August-November 1982, 1 expandable folder (Box 67)
    - Record Book 1979 of the Committee to Review Clinical Chairman Search Procedures, 1 expandable folder (Box 67)
  - Finance and Personnel Committee
    - Minutes
      - June 1978-August 1979, 4 volumes (Box 67)
      - September 1979-May 1981, 5 volumes (Box 72)
      - June 1981-June 1983, 6 volumes (Box 73)
      - January 1983-February 1986, 3 volumes (Box 82)
  - Hospital Advisory Group/Executive Team
    - Hospital Advisory Group (HAG)
      - January 1988-September 1990 (Box 97)
    - Hospital Executive Team (HET)
      - January-December 1998 (continues as Hospital Advisory Group) (Box 97)
  - Joint Conference Committee
    - Minutes (Box 63)
      - June 1978-September 1979, 5 volumes (Box 63)
      - September 1979-August 1981, 5 volumes (Box 64)
      - September 1981-February 1983, 3 volumes (Box 65)
    - Minutes
      - March 1983-December 1983 (Box 81)
      - January 1984-February 1986, 3 volumes (Box 82)
  - Joint Staff (University Hospital-Medical School)
    - Minutes (Box 67)
      - April 1976-September 1980, 5 expandable folders (Box 67)
      - September 1980-April 1982, 6 expandable folders (Box 68)
      - April 1982-May 1983, 5 expandable folders (Box 69)
      - May 1983-September 1984, 5 expandable folders (Box 70)
      - September-December 1984, 1 expandable folder (Box 71)
  - Management Committee
    - Clinical Delivery Systems Executive Committee (CDSEC) Minutes (Box 84)
      - May 1995-April 1997 (Box 84)
      - April 1997-December 1997 (Box 85)
    - Clinical Delivery Systems Management Team (CDSMT)/Systems Management Team (SMT) Minutes
      - May 1995-December 1997 (Box 85)
    - Executive Committee on Clinical Affairs (ECCA) Minutes (Box 86)
      - June 16, 1975-November 28, 1995, 7 volumes (Box 86)
      - October 2, 1979-December 23, 1980, 6 volumes (Box 87)
      - January 6, 1981-April 27, 1982, 6 volumes (Box 88)
      - May 4, 1982-May 10, 1983, 6 volumes (Box 89)
      - May 17, 1983-March 26, 1985, 8 volumes (Box 90)
      - April 23, 1985-March 28, 1989, 7 volumes (Box 91)
      - April 25, 1989-May 25, 1993 (Box 92)
  - Medical Staff
    - Medical Staff Lists 1922-1964, 2 volumes (Box 100)
    - Medical Staff Statistics 1977-1981, 2 volumes (Box 100)
    - Medical Staff Lists and Statistics 1983-1989, 4 folders (Box 101)
    - House Officer Data 1955-1986, 11 folders (Box 101)
    - House Officer PGY's 1983-1988, 1 volume (Box 101)
  - Planning/Public Advisory Committee
    - Planning Advisory Committee (Box 60)
      - Minutes July 1977-June 1979, 5 volumes (Box 60)
      - Minutes July 1979-December 1981, 5 volumes (Box 61)
        (continues as the Public Advisory Board)
    - Public Advisory Committee
      - Minutes December 1983-March 1985 (Box 61)
    - Public Advisory Board (Box 62)
      - Minutes January 1982-July 1983, 5 volumes (Box 62)
  - Staff Meeting
    - Bole/Forsyth Staff Meetings (Box 97)
      - September 1995-May 1996, 1 folder (Box 97)
    - Joint Staff Meetings July 1993-June 1994, 6 folders (Box 97)
    - Clinical Department Minutes
      - 1990
        - Anesthesiology (Box 97)
        - Dermatology (Box 97)
        - Internal Medicine (Box 97)
        - Obstetrics/Gynecology (Box 97)
        - Ophthalmology (Box 97)
        - Otolaryngology (Box 97)
        - Pathology (Box 97)
        - Pediatrics (Box 97)
        - Radiation Oncology (Box 97)
        - Radiology (Box 97)
        - Death or Complication Reports (Box 97)
      - 1991 (Box 98)
        - Anesthesiology (Box 98)
        - Dentistry (Box 98)
        - Dermatology (Box 98)
        - Internal Medicine (Box 98)
        - Nuclear Medicine (Box 98)
        - Obstetrics/Gynecology (Box 98)
        - Ophthalmology (Box 98)
        - Otolaryngology (Box 98)
        - Pediatrics (Box 98)
        - Psychiatry (Box 98)
        - Radiology (Box 98)
        - Oral Surgery (Box 98)
        - Death or Complication Reports (Box 98)
      - 1992
        - Anesthesiology (Box 98)
        - Dentistry (Box 98)
        - Dermatology (Box 98)
        - Internal Medicine (Box 98)
        - Neurology (Box 98)
        - Obstetrics/Gynecology (Box 98)
        - Ophthalmology (Box 98)
        - Otolaryngology (Box 98)
        - Pathology (Box 98)
        - Pediatrics (Box 98)
        - Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation (Box 98)
        - Radiation Oncology (Box 98)
        - Radiology (Box 98)
        - Death or Complication Reports (Box 98)
      - 1993
        - Anesthesiology (Box 98)
        - Dentistry (Box 98)
        - Internal Medicine (Box 98)
        - Obstetrics/Gynecology (Box 98)
        - Ophthalmology (Box 98)
        - Otolaryngology (Box 98)
        - Radiology (Box 98)
        - General Surgery (Box 98)
        - Death or Complication Reports (Box 98)
      - 1994
        - Anesthesiology (Box 98)
        - Dentistry (Box 98)
        - Dermatology (Box 98)
        - Internal Medicine (Box 98)
        - Nuclear Medicine (Box 98)
        - Obstetrics/Gynecology (Box 98)
        - Ophthalmology (Box 98)
        - Otolaryngology (Box 98)
        - Radiology (Box 98)
        - Death or Complication Reports (Box 98)
      - 1995
        - Anesthesiology (Box 98)
        - Dermatology (Box 98)
        - Internal Medicine (Box 98)
        - Ophthalmology (Box 98)
        - Otolaryngology (Box 98)
        - Radiology (Box 98)
    - Medical Staff Standing Committees (MSSC) (Box 99)
      - September 1974-June 1991 (Box 99)
      - July 1992-June 1993 (Box 100)
    - Medical Staff Quarterly Meetings
      - October 1982-November 1988 (Box 100)
- Patient Files
  The Patient Files series (14 linear feet) contains records pertaining to the patients of the hospital system. This series is split into 4 sub series: Case Records, Hospital Reports, Hospital School for Patients, and Record Books/Registration Books. Some of the records contained within this series are restricted as described in the access restrictions page of the finding aid. The records within these subseries include case files, hospital registration books, and other patient files.
  - Case Records
    [CR RESTRICTED access: 100 years from the date of creation]
    - Dermatology Clinic 1890-1892 and 1893-1899, 3 volumes (Box 2)
    - Department of Ophthalmology and Otology 1890-1892, 1 volume (Box 2)
    - Orthopedic Case Records 1924, 1 volume (Box 2)
      [CR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2024 ]
    - Obstetrics Case Records 1909 and 1919, 2 volumes (Box 3)
      [CR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2019 ]
    - Gynecology Case Records 1881-1882 and 1919, 2 volumes (Box 3)
    - Neurology Case Records 1892-1899, 3 volumes (Box 4)
    - Pathology 1891-1892, 1 volume (Box 4)
    - Outpatient Records 1891-1892, 1 volume (Box 4)
    - General Surgery Case Records 1919 and 1924, 3 volumes (Box 5)
    - Records (unspecified) 1910-1911, 1 volume (Box 5)
    - Ward Reports of the Superintendent of Nurses, circa 1913-1919 (Box 6)
    - Ward Reports of the Superintendent of Nurses, circa 1913-1919 (continued) (Box 7)
    - Ward Reports of the Superintendent of Nurses, circa 1913-1919 (continued) (Box 8)
    - Record of Operations-Clinic of Otolaryngology 1926-1929, 1933-1935 and 1941-1962, 4 volumes (Box 9)
      [CR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2062 ]
  - Hospital Reports
    - Papers 1875-1896 relating to the construction of the Hospital Building and its addition (Box 1)
    - Reports (include reports to the Board of Regents 1877-1878 and 1879-1880 committee reports on University Hospital, 1883, 1888 and 1891 and undated report of Abram Sager (Box 1)
    - Report 1928 on Equipment Replacement Program for University Hospital (Box 1)
    - Report 1904-1905 of the Surgical Department by C.B.G. de Nancrede (Box 1)
    - Copy of University Hospital payroll July 1904-February 1905 (Box 1)
    - Papers, circa 1920 concerning building programs of University Hospital (Box 1)
      (include correspondence and statistical data)
    - Miscellany (Box 1)
      (include rules and regulations for administration of affairs in University Hospital; accounts, circa 1912-1915 invitation to the officials of Ann Arbor to attend opening of Contagious Disease Hospital)
    - Report 1945 of the Records Committee of the Advisory Staff, University Hospital (Box 1)
    - Schedule of equipment of the Psychopathic Hospital undated (Box 1)
    - Minutes 1892-1908 of Hospital Committee (Box 1)
    - Minutes, circa 1892-1914 of Hospital Committee [typescript copy; fragmentary] (Box 1)
    - History of the University Hospital by Reuben Peterson, 5 volumes (Box 1)
    - Hospital Day-Night Reports, 3 volumes (Box 1)
      (condition of patients)
    - February 20-March 28, 1917 (Box 1)
    - June 21-August 1, 1917 (Box 1)
    - October 14-December 16, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Time Reports for Hospital Personnel, 3 volumes (Box 1)
    - October 1914-April 1915 (Box 1)
    - December 1915-June 1916 (Box 1)
    - September 1918-March 1919 (Box 1)
    - Personnel Assignments (nurses), 3 volumes (Box 1)
    - April 6-August 29, 1915 (Box 1)
    - November 10-December 18, 1920 (Box 1)
    - December 19, 1920-February 28, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports (Box 24)
      (Hospital Departments)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 24)
      - 1960-1961
        - A-N (Box 24)
        - O-Z (Box 24)
      - 1961-1962
        - A-M (Box 24)
        - N-Z (Box 24)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 24)
      - 1963-1964, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 25)
      - 1966-1967, 2 folders (Box 25)
      - 1967-1968, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Capital Outlays: 1958-1964 (Box 25)
    - General Policy Notebook 1943-1944 (Box 25)
    - Newspaper Clippings
      - 1947-1954 (Box 25)
      - 1954-1964 (Box 25)
      - 1965-1969 (Box 26)
      - 1969-1972 (Box 26)
      - 1972-1975 (Box 26)
      - 1953-1970, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Standard Practices Book 1933-1952, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Hospital School for Patients
    - Annual Reports 1923-1950 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 18)
  - Record Books/Registration Books
    - Pediatrics Cases, Record Book 1885-1888 (Volume 1)
      (Bimu/C500)
      Closed to research
    - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975
      74749-1385601
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 2)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 3)
        (continued)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 4)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 5)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 6)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 7)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 8)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 9)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 10)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 11)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 12)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 13)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 14)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 15)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 16)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 17)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 18)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 19)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 20)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 21)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 22)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 23)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 24)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 25)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 26)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 27)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 28)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 29)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 30)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 31)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 32)
      - Patient Registration Books July 1923-April 1975 (Volume 33)
- Hospital Buildings
  The Hospital Buildings series (18 linear feet) contains the designs and documentation of the various hospital buildings. The series is split into the Architectural Drawings and Replacement Hospital Project subseries. The bulk of this series consists of documents relating to the design and construction of new hospital buildings as well as the renovation of existing hospital structures, including meeting minutes and executive reports.
  - Architectural Drawings
    - Replacement Hospital Plans (Microfiche)
      - Replacement Hospital Plans (Microfiche) (Box 40)
      - Replacement Hospital Plans (Microfiche) (Box 41)
      - Replacement Hospital Plans (Microfiche) (Box 42)
      - Replacement Hospital Plans (Microfiche) (Box 43)
      - Replacement Hospital Plans (Microfiche) (Box 44)
      - Replacement Hospital Plans (Microfiche) (Box 45)
      - Replacement Hospital Plans (Microfiche) (Box 46)
      - Replacement Hospital Plans (Microfiche) (Box 47)
      - Replacement Hospital Plans (Microfiche) (Box 48)
    - Architectural Drawings, University Hospital 1921, 10 items (Folder Bimu/C500)
  - Replacement Hospital Project 1970-1984
    - Chronological Files
      - 1970-July 1975, 3 volumes (Box 28)
      - August 1975-April 1976, 3 volumes (Box 29)
      - May 1976-1977, 4 volumes (Box 30)
      - January-September 1978 (Box 31)
      - October 1978-March 1979, 4 volumes (Box 32)
      - April-August 1979 (Box 33)
      - September 1979-April 1980 (Box 34)
    - Executive reports 1980-1983, 3 volumes (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 39)
    - Groundbreaking ceremony for Replacement Hospital, 1 volume (Box 39)
    - W.K. Kellogg Eye Center Naming and Groundbreaking Ceremony April 25, 1983, 1 volume (Box 39)
    - Weekly Meetings of the RHP Executive Steering Committee April 1980-June 1984, 5 volumes (Box 49)
      (also called "Shapiro Breakfast Meetings" and consisting of the president, the vice-president for academic affairs, the vice-president and chief financial officer, the director of the University Hospital, the dean of the Medical School, and the vice-president for state relations)